# Jocelyn Carr

(they/them)
User Experience | Software Development | Human Factors
jocelyn.carr132@gmail.com • jcarr.xyz

I'm a user experience researcher and software developer specializing in human factors in technology. I am primarily interested in understanding the complex and evolving relationship between people and our technology; how we create and shape technology which in turn shapes us as individuals and as a global society. I believe in technology as a shared tool of empowerment that should contribute to the betterment of life for all people.

## Experience

**Business Analyst** 

Digital HR, Department of National Defence (Remote, Canada)

July 2021 - Present

- Worked in a Product Management role for DND Careers, a recruitment platform for the Department of National Defence which hosts over 3500 user accounts.
- Applied user-centric design principles in an Agile development environment.
- Requirements analysis, developing acceptance criteria, writing user stories technical specifications.
- Worked closely with stakeholders to prioritize issues and deliver business value.
- Provided progress reports and status updates to senior management.

**Junior Business Analyst** 

Strategic Directions, Service Canada (Gatineau, Québec, Canada)

May 2019 - April 2020

- Conducted quantitative data analysis on various organizational data sources using R to support and inform business decision-making.
- Developed data visualizations, reports, and research proposals.
- Generated qualitative artifacts including Personas, Journey Maps, and Service Blueprints.

#### Research Assistant

Carleton University (Ottawa, Ontario, Canada)

September 2018 - September 2020

- Designed and built a prototype user-authentication system for brain-computer interface devices using JavaScript and MongoDB.
- Conducted in person usability testing as well as remote semi-structured interviewing and online surveys.
- Performed statistical data analysis and hypothesis testing using R.

#### **Teaching Assistant**

Carleton University (Ottawa, Ontario, Canada)

September 2018 - January 2020

- Assisted with administration of several courses in the domain of interactive multimedia.
- Courses included Advanced Visual Effects, Introduction to Interactive Multimedia, and Advanced Topics in Multimedia.

Polysomnograph Technologist

Trent Regional Sleep Clinic (Peterborough, Ontario, Canada) May 2017 - August 2018

Teaching Assistant Trent University (Peterborough, Ontario, Canada) September 2015 - January 2018

Research Assistant Trent University (Peterborough, Ontario, Canada) September 2013 - January 2017

## Education

Master of Applied Science in Human-Computer Interaction September 2018 - September 2020 Carleton University (Ottawa, Ontario, Canada)

Bachelor of Science (Honours) in Psychology September 2011 - April 2015 Trent University (Peterborough, Ontario, Canada)

### Skills

- Technologies: Azure DevOps, Git & GitHub, Linux/Unix, Bash, R, JavaScript/HTML/CSS, Python, Go, MongoDB,
- Hard Skills: Software Project Management, User-Centric Design, User Research, UX Evaluation, Requirements Analysis, Technical Writing, Agile/Scrum, Data Analytics, Research, Data Visualization.
- Soft Skills: Analytical Thinking, Prioritization, Adaptability, Team-Orientation, Technology Literacy, Communication, Knowledge Management, Stakeholder Collaboration, Remote Teams,